I am aware that I am inhaling, I am aware that I am exhaling, I am following my
私は息を吸っていることを意識し、息を吐いていることを意識し、私は私の
breath, I become aware of my body, I relax my body, I generate
呼吸であり、自分の体に気づき、体を緩め、私は生み出す
a feeling of joy, I generate a feeling of happiness in
喜びの感情を、私は幸福感を
the present.
現在に。
I become aware of my pain, I embrace my pain, I take care of it.
私は自分の痛みに気づき、痛みを受け入れ、それを大切にする。
It's important to have good motivation when you're going to start meditating.
瞑想を始める際には、適切な動機を持つことが重要です。
will present you with obstacles. The first obstacle you
あなたに障害をもたらすでしょう。あなたが
will encounter is laziness. It will
遭遇する最初の障害は怠惰です。それは
bring you a second subtlety, which is called active laziness. I was doing a
さらに第二の微妙な点、活動的な怠惰と呼ばれるものをもたらすでしょう。私は
lot of things except going to meditate. A third laziness that still arises is
瞑想に行くこと以外に多くのことをしていました。さらに現れる第三の怠惰は
giving up. But
諦めです。しかし
then you tell yourself no, ultimately it's not for me. The antidote
その時、あなたは「いや、結局これは私には向いていない」と思うでしょう。その解毒剤は
is to find a just motivation.
適切な動機を見つけることです。
This motivation must be
この動機は
not only for you, but also for others.
あなた自身のためだけでなく、他者のためでもなければなりません。
The second real obstacle you will encounter,
あなたが遭遇する第二の真の障害は、
is that when you learn to meditate,
瞑想を学ぶ際に、
initially, there is a methodology in learning.
当初、学習には方法論があるということです。
The obstacle you will encounter is the complete forgetting of what needs to be done.
あなたが遭遇する障害は、何をすべきかを完全に忘れてしまうことです。
At one point, I was meditating,
ある時、私は瞑想をしていました。
well, I thought I was meditating,
いや、瞑想をしているつもりでした。
I was sitting there, ultimately, I was dreaming quite a bit.
私はそこに座っていましたが、結局はかなり夢想していました。
I understood that meditation is a training of the mind.
瞑想とは精神の訓練であると理解しました。
It comes from a very ancient etymology that means...
それは非常に古い語源に由来し、その意味するところは…
Truly learning to discover one's own functioning.
真に自分自身の機能を発見することを学ぶことです。
You're not always well when you meditate, but that's okay.
瞑想する際に常に調子が良いとは限りませんが、それは問題ありません。
I learn to recognize, to train my mind.
私は自分の精神を認識し、訓練することを学びます。
And the antidote, which I think is very interesting for us in the practice of meditation,
そして、瞑想の実践において私たちにとって非常に興味深いと思う解毒剤は、
is attention, it's mindfulness.
注意、すなわちマインドフルネスです。
Discovering this energy that is in your mind, this energy that is concentration,
あなたの精神の中にあるこのエネルギー、集中力であるこのエネルギーを発見すること、
and which will gradually open you to another energy which is the deep vision of things.
そしてそれは徐々に、物事の深遠な洞察という別のエネルギーへとあなたを開いていくでしょう。
But you have to go little by little.
しかし、徐々に進む必要があります。
It's like when you enter a space or on the walls.
それは、あなたが空間に入る時、あるいは壁に、
There are secrets that can be revealed.
明らかにされ得る秘密があるようなものです。
I enter with a candle, and the candle is your mind.
私は一本のろうそくを持って入ります。そのろうそくはあなたの精神です。
Initially, the candle moves like this, which means there's not really any brightness.
最初はろうそくの炎は揺れ動き、それは真の明るさがないことを意味します。
But if through the practice of your meditation, the base, you learn to completely stabilize the flame,
しかし、もしあなたが瞑想の実践、つまり基本によって、炎を完全に安定させることを学ぶなら、
a kind of luminous halo appears, a kind of clarity emerges.
ある種の光の輪が現れ、ある種の明瞭さが生じます。
Well, it's a bit the same thing.
それはまさに同じようなことです。
If you really manage to stabilize your mind, all of a sudden you will perceive a kind of
もしあなたが本当に精神を安定させることができれば、突然、ある種の
luminous clarity.
光明な明瞭さを知覚するでしょう。
that appears in one's mind. This clarity leads you to deep vision.
あなたの精神に現れる光明な明瞭さ。この明瞭さは、あなたを深遠な洞察へと導きます。
You have to learn
学ぶ必要があります。
to stabilize the mind because it's a whole work of stabilization. So
精神を安定させることを。なぜなら、それは安定化の全作業だからです。したがって、
it's learning
それは学ぶことです。
to develop this clarity of mind first through the energy of mindfulness,
まずマインドフルネスのエネルギーを通して、この精神の明瞭さを発展させることを学ぶことです。
the energy of concentration and the energy of deep vision.
集中力のエネルギー、そして深遠な洞察のエネルギーを通して。
You have
必要です。
to train. Everyone can have access to this.
訓練することが。誰もがこれにアクセスできます。